

MUHAMMAD ALI WILDAN

BACKEND ENGINER | WEB DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

Passion and enthusiastic, I am interested in the world of IT and all that is in its scope,

I am very enthusiastic and really enjoy my work as a Web developer, especially backend, I like to solve existing problems with technological solutions, especially WEB and also I like to share my experience and knowledge with others.

SKILLS

- Programming Languange : PHP,Java,Javascript,Html/Css.
- Framework : Laravel, Codeigniter, Node Js, Vue js, Bootstrap, Tailwind.
- Project Development Management : Scrum-Agile Development..
- Versioning Control : Github and Gitlab..
- Database: Mysql, Postgre Sql,Mongo DB, Oracle

CONTACT

- Sembunganya Rt 06 No 41 ,Dukun , Kab Gresik.
- Email:aliwildan99@gmail.com.
- Nomor Ponsel: 087752921742.
- Linkedin

 https://www.linkedin.com/in/ali
 wildan/.
- Github : wildanicardi.

EXPERIENCE

internship

PT. Lanius Inovasi Indonesia (January 2019 - February 2019)

• build display human machine interface for OEEE using Vue Js, Electron Js and Node js

Work

Isocorp Technology, Freelance (April 2019 - May 2019)

 At Iscorp I created a certification services marketplace, using Laravel for backend and bootstrap for front end

PT.HJS, Freelance (October 2019 - Desember 2019)

 Work in team, create cargo delivery service applications, position me as a developer backend to create APIs using Laravel framework

Negeri Baja, Freelance (January 2020- April 2020)

- Create design system, use case Diagram of Bhaskara Futsal Surabaya office management application.
- Create design system, use case diagrams and business flow elearning applications

EDUCATION

Politeknik elektronika negeri surabaya

Associate Bachelor, Informatics Engineering(2017 - 2020)

- Programming Concept
- Logic & Algorithm,
- Object Oriented Programming,.
- Web Design and Development, .
- Network Administration, Network Security, .
- Basic Database, Management Database.

VOLUNTERING EXPERINECE

Surabaya dev community (2018-2019)
 SurabayaDev is an IT community that help improve and utilize the potential of IT activists throughout Indonesia, especially in the city of Surabaya in the field of echnology, to support, to realize a complementary condition in order to increase expertise, and the spirit of cooperation.

PROFESSIONAL PROJECT

- COMBO, COMBO is a web-based application regarding the logistics retail business. using a web platform and also an android
- Maskumambang Attandance, Application of attendance and schedule of vocational teachers in Maskumambang Gresik Vocational School.
- Bluanddis, Bluanddis is a web promotion and order design services Acrylic.
- HMI OEE(Overall Equipment.Effectiveness), Display the machine interface in real time monitoring the performance of the machine at the factory
- Surabaya Dev Profile, is a Web profile for the community of developers inSurabaya, containing information about technology, events and competitions.

PERSONAL PROJECT

 HEWANQ, Hewanq is a pet marketplace app, and animal care and consulting.

BOOTCAMP EXPERIENCE

MamiCamp Backend Engineer Participant

MAMIKOS (May 2020 - june 2020)

 Bootcamp backend focuses on the basic expertise of a backend developer such as OOP concepts, design patterns, etc., using the PHP programming language, and the Laravel framework, Tailwind CSS and MYSQL DB to build web applications

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Belajar dasar pemrograman web- Dicoding academy 2019

 in this certification I learned about creating web designs from the basics including using html, css, and basic javascript, and learning about frameworks, such as bootstrap and jquery

Pembuatan aplikasi web dinamis- badan nasiona sertifikasi profesi 2019

 in this certification I learned about web development technology dynamically using the php programming language.

Sertifikat Fundamental web front end DICODING ACADEMY 2020

• in this certification I learned about web design development technology using javascript technology, such as ES6, npm, webpack, etc.

Progressive Web Apps The Complete Guideudemy online course 2020

• in this certification i learned about create web development mode progressive web apps

belajar prinsip pemrograman solid- dicoding Academy 2020

 in this certification i learned about solid principle in programming, like Single Responsibility Principle (SRP) Open/Close Principle (OCP) Liskov Substitution Principle (LSP) Interface Segregation Principle (ISP) Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP)

Path Pengembangan WEB- PROGATE 2020

• in this certification i learned about creating dynamic web using js node technology, and mysql database